Speaker1: What position was
Speaker1: he hired for? Uh,
Speaker1: brand
Speaker1: ambassador
Speaker1: for,
Speaker1: um,
Speaker1: bows
Speaker1: a weekend
Speaker1: event, a six
Speaker1: week program for
Speaker1: a weekend event.
Speaker1: It's
Speaker1: darted the
Speaker1: fifth of
Speaker1: September, I believe,
Speaker1: and runs through
Speaker1: October 12th.
Speaker1: Um,
Speaker1: and he was aware that
Speaker1: there was an end
Speaker1: date. I'm
Speaker1: sorry. Yes.
Speaker1: Um,
Speaker1: I actually clarified
Speaker1: that with him
Speaker1: like three
Speaker1: times.
Speaker1: Um, to
Speaker1: make sure that he
Speaker1: understood that it was a
Speaker1: Friday,
Speaker1: Saturday,
Speaker1: Sunday
Speaker1: position and that
Speaker1: he was available
Speaker1: for the full 6
Speaker1: weekends.
Speaker1: Like, I'm pretty
Speaker1: sure that's what
Speaker1: happened.
Speaker1: Um,
Speaker1: it's.
Speaker1: It's amazing what
Speaker1: people hear
Speaker1: versus what you
Speaker1: say, but what I
Speaker1: would like
Speaker1: Cindy is, do you
Speaker1: have
Speaker1: by
Speaker1: chance any.
Speaker1: Can we easily
Speaker1: see like what
Speaker1: exactly he was
Speaker1: offered? And
Speaker1: if you've got
Speaker1: like text
Speaker1: conversations with
Speaker1: him, I know he's
Speaker1: gonna go off the rails
Speaker1: when I talk to him,
Speaker1: but I do wanna
Speaker1: have something I can
Speaker1: look at and refer
Speaker1: to
Speaker1: when
Speaker1: I talk
Speaker1: to him to kind of
Speaker1: keep us
Speaker1: grounded.
Speaker1: Yeah, I can
Speaker1: send you
Speaker1: the
Speaker1: call log
Speaker1: from our first
Speaker1: call,
Speaker1: the very first
Speaker1: communication I had
Speaker1: with him that
Speaker1: clearly,
Speaker1: You can see in
Speaker1: here, it
Speaker1: talks
Speaker1: about the
Speaker1: days.
Speaker1: Hold on, let me go back
Speaker1: to it. I just
Speaker1: actually sent this over to
Speaker1: Jerry. Yeah,
Speaker2: we have the
Speaker2: transcripts,
Speaker2: which are like a
Speaker2: rough recording of
Speaker2: these dialogues.
Speaker2: And so we've got
Speaker2: that
Speaker2: followed by any
Speaker2: of
Speaker2: the
Speaker2: text
Speaker2: exchanges as
Speaker2: well.
Speaker2: sorry that I was
Speaker2: late. I was on with
Speaker2: Juliet. So
Speaker2: I had to get
Speaker2: something for Brett real
Speaker2: quick.
Speaker2: So my
Speaker2: bad.
Speaker2: Cindy, I'm not.
Speaker2: I didn't leave you
Speaker2: alone.
Speaker2: Not with
Speaker2: me,
Speaker2: Latasha.
Speaker2: I would never.
Speaker1: Wait, what?
Speaker1: kidding.
Speaker1: Jerry.
Speaker2: Hey, I'm
Speaker2: teasing. She
Speaker2: knows the best. I
Speaker1: know you just got
Speaker1: back from
Speaker1: vacation, but
Speaker1: tone it down a
Speaker1: little bit.
Speaker1: Yes,
Speaker1: Tone it down.
Speaker1: You can't-
Speaker2: Luckily, P.A.
Speaker2: is not on his
Speaker2: call. Sheesh.
Speaker2: She's
Speaker1: just getting to
Speaker1: know me, and
Speaker1: you're already
Speaker1: starting her off on
Speaker1: the wrong
Speaker2: foot.
Speaker2: No,
Speaker2: she
Speaker2: knows.
Speaker1: Meanwhile, it
Speaker1: was like, oh, my God,
Speaker1: this is what happened when
Speaker1: I involve
Speaker1: HR.
Speaker1: No, no, no,
Speaker1: no, no.
Speaker1: Keep calling me,
Speaker1: please.
Speaker2: Yeah, it's,
Speaker2: you know, it
Speaker2: happens once
Speaker2: every 6
Speaker2: months we get.
Speaker2: We get 1 of these,
Speaker2: you know,
Speaker2: it happens.
Speaker2: More than ever the
Speaker2: clues, you just
Speaker2: flash.
Speaker2: Maybe not closing
Speaker2: it, but the
Speaker2: advanced
Speaker2: method
Speaker2: of sharing
Speaker2: reps across
Speaker2: these programs
Speaker2: that we've implemented
Speaker2: over the last couple of
Speaker2: months.
Speaker2: Does make it
Speaker2: harder than it
Speaker2: probably
Speaker2: used to
Speaker1: That didn't open
Speaker1: for me.
Speaker1: As far as I could do
Speaker1: open.
Speaker2: I'm sorry, was that a
Speaker2: question? I
Speaker2: couldn't hear you,
Speaker2: Diana.
Speaker1: Oh, so sorry.
Speaker1: Cindy sent over.
Speaker1: Oh, never mind. Now
Speaker1: I came through. I don't
Speaker1: know. My computer's been
Speaker1: acting crazy all day.
Speaker2: No worries.
Speaker1: OK,
Speaker1: perfect.
Speaker1: So it looks
Speaker1: like
Speaker1: the transcript
Speaker1: itself is
Speaker1: you might have to like piece
Speaker1: together some
Speaker1: parts to it like
Speaker1: you could the
Speaker1: language barrier
Speaker1: because he's got a really
Speaker1: strong
Speaker1: accent. So
Speaker1: some of the.
Speaker1: Some
Speaker2: of the words look
Speaker1: funny.
Speaker1: I see what
Speaker1: it
Speaker1: says quite
Speaker1: clearly is
Speaker1: about the
Speaker1: weekends, and I'm more
Speaker1: looking for what
Speaker1: you said to
Speaker1: him.
Speaker1: You can see where it
Speaker1: says the 23
Speaker1: an hour, because I know that
Speaker1: was one of the other things
Speaker1: he
Speaker1: mentioned multiple
Speaker1: times. I
Speaker1: told him 24,
Speaker1: but I didn't. I
Speaker1: told him 23. And
Speaker1: his offer letter says
Speaker1: 23. The
Speaker1: job posting on
Speaker1: Trusted Heard says
Speaker1: 23.
Speaker1: So
Speaker1: I'm not sure where
Speaker1: he got 24
Speaker1: from.
Speaker1: Probably
Speaker1: the same place he
Speaker1: heard that this was a
Speaker1: full-time
Speaker1: job.
Speaker1: It's clear that he
Speaker1: understands here.
Speaker1: He even repeats
Speaker1: it.
Speaker1: I
Speaker1: figured that was going to
Speaker1: be the case, but
Speaker1: I needed to meet
Speaker1: with you guys so
Speaker1: that I could
Speaker1: actually
Speaker1: get those
Speaker1: details.
Speaker1: So,
Speaker1: Gerardo, now
Speaker1: let's move
Speaker1: to to
Speaker1: what started
Speaker1: happening
Speaker1: after
Speaker1: that.
Speaker1: Because I do
Speaker1: see where
Speaker1: he was
Speaker1: basically
Speaker1: spamming
Speaker1: the
Speaker1: team's chats
Speaker1: and why we would have
Speaker1: removed him from
Speaker1: those chats.
Speaker1: But
Speaker1: what was the
Speaker1: the reason why we
Speaker1: said he was
Speaker1: threatening?
Speaker2: Yeah, so I
Speaker2: mean,
Speaker2: So I really started
Speaker2: communicating with them just
Speaker2: like the last two weeks,
Speaker2: though, because
Speaker2: this
Speaker2: program,
Speaker2: these
Speaker2: reports to
Speaker2: Joe
Speaker2: Pacino's
Speaker2: field
Speaker2: managers.
Speaker2: And
Speaker2: they're a
Speaker2: little busy right now with
Speaker2: so many things.
Speaker2: And this
Speaker2: program,
Speaker2: really this
Speaker2: Costco is a
Speaker2: test. If we
Speaker2: were
Speaker2: successful, were there
Speaker2: sales,
Speaker2: then we might
Speaker2: get more work from them.
Speaker2: So I actually
Speaker2: stepped in the last
Speaker2: two weeks to
Speaker2: have team
Speaker2: calls just
Speaker2: to
Speaker2: talk to them about
Speaker2: sales training,
Speaker2: how to engage a
Speaker2: customer
Speaker2: at
Speaker2: Costco, get a
Speaker2: hook and all that
Speaker2: kind of stuff. So
Speaker2: my interaction just
Speaker2: really
Speaker2: started,
Speaker2: about two weeks
Speaker2: ago and
Speaker2: the
Speaker2: first, was that
Speaker2: email that I already
Speaker2: forwarded to you
Speaker2: where he
Speaker2: was just talking
Speaker2: about,
Speaker2: you know,
Speaker2: T-ROC
Speaker2: and
Speaker2: discrimination
Speaker2: and,
Speaker2: know, the white
Speaker2: man and just
Speaker2: kind of just scrunchles
Speaker2: about
Speaker2: that. So I actually
Speaker2: called him
Speaker2: after
Speaker2: that and I just
Speaker2: said, when
Speaker2: Anish, I got your
Speaker2: email and I
Speaker2: said, it
Speaker2: seems like you're just
Speaker2: frustrated. Do you not
Speaker2: want to do the
Speaker2: program
Speaker2: anymore?
Speaker2: Because he
Speaker2: was,
Speaker2: I'm playing about
Speaker2: our, about
Speaker2: our incentives,
Speaker2: whatnot. And,
Speaker2: and I said, I said,
Speaker2: you know, I,
Speaker2: I get your
Speaker2: frustration. I
Speaker2: said, I
Speaker2: can't, I wish I could
Speaker2: fix the world. I can't
Speaker2: fix the world, but what I
Speaker2: can do is help you
Speaker2: with sales on this,
Speaker2: you know, my focus is
Speaker2: program. He
Speaker2: apologized.
Speaker2: Um,
Speaker2: and, and then we left at
Speaker2: that
Speaker2: really. And
Speaker2: then on
Speaker2: Wednesday, or
Speaker2: I'm sorry, this
Speaker2: Friday is when he
Speaker2: started.
Speaker2: with the
Speaker2: bombardments of
Speaker2: text messages
Speaker2: on
Speaker2: the chats.
Speaker2: So
Speaker2: I thought that
Speaker2: Storm had calmed,
Speaker2: because I
Speaker2: thought maybe he didn't
Speaker2: want to work
Speaker2: on the program. And
Speaker2: then I
Speaker2: hadn't not talked to him
Speaker2: really after that.
Speaker2: And then you
Speaker2: saw the text
Speaker2: messages that he
Speaker2: started
Speaker2: posting there. And
Speaker2: I'm going to sue you.
Speaker2: Well,
Speaker2: actually, I'll take it back. I
Speaker2: did call on
Speaker2: Friday.
Speaker2: I did talk to him on
Speaker2: Friday
Speaker2: because I
Speaker2: couldn't turn off the
Speaker2: chat. And I said,
Speaker2: oh, you know,
Speaker2: I'll take the back. I did
Speaker2: talk to him,
Speaker2: but I
Speaker2: realized I couldn't.
Speaker2: He was not
Speaker2: talkable.
Speaker2: He was just
Speaker2: frustrated and,
Speaker2: you know, started
Speaker2: threatening and
Speaker2: all that kind of stuff,
Speaker2: you know. Right. But
Speaker1: he was
Speaker1: threatening to
Speaker1: sue. But what
Speaker1: else was he threatening?
Speaker1: Was he threatening
Speaker1: anything other than he
Speaker1: was going to sue?
Speaker2: He
Speaker2: well, it's so
Speaker2: with
Speaker2: Well, he was threatening,
Speaker2: because he was just
Speaker2: going off, and
Speaker2: by then I was
Speaker2: trying to figure out how to
Speaker2: kind of get off the phone.
Speaker2: But yeah, so
Speaker2: on that call, and
Speaker2: I wish, I don't have
Speaker2: transcripts or
Speaker2: the call record, but
Speaker2: yeah, one that
Speaker2: we're gonna sue,
Speaker2: one
Speaker2: you know, if we're gonna
Speaker2: discriminate
Speaker2: against them, that he's
Speaker2: gonna
Speaker2: sue us,
Speaker2: and
Speaker2: then in
Speaker2: the,
Speaker2: text message he
Speaker2: sent me
Speaker2: was
Speaker2: saying that
Speaker2: if I'm
Speaker2: gonna discriminate
Speaker2: against him,
Speaker2: he knows people at
Speaker2: Bose,
Speaker2: Costco. I
Speaker2: think
Speaker2: I sent you
Speaker2: that text message,
Speaker2: right?
Speaker2: have
Speaker2: call recordings I can
Speaker2: share
Speaker2: from
Speaker2: you.
Speaker2: So
Speaker2: that's when he started, and
Speaker2: I'll send you that text, he
Speaker2: started just
Speaker2: threatening, just in
Speaker2: general, just saying,
Speaker2: if you were
Speaker2: at Title VIII,
Speaker2: well,
Speaker2: you know, I'm
Speaker2: gonna call
Speaker2: Bose, I'm gonna call
Speaker2: Costco, and,
Speaker2: which I wasn't gonna,
Speaker2: you know, I
Speaker2: did not respond to that
Speaker2: text message,
Speaker2: you know, but
Speaker2: he's saying if you
Speaker2: retaliate, well
Speaker2: then, you know,
Speaker2: this is what I'm gonna do.
Speaker2: So by then I said, you
Speaker2: know, I'm not gonna call him,
Speaker2: I'm not gonna text him
Speaker2: anymore.
Speaker1: Yeah, but I'm
Speaker1: trying to get,
Speaker1: did he threaten
Speaker1: you with
Speaker1: physical
Speaker1: bottling
Speaker1: harm?
Speaker2: Oh,
Speaker2: physical,
Speaker2: no, no, no,
Speaker2: not like,
Speaker2: nothing like I'm
Speaker2: gonna, you
Speaker2: know, no, nothing
Speaker2: physical like that,
Speaker2: not, not.
Speaker1: So on
Speaker1: Friday, on
Speaker1: Friday, when we
Speaker1: spoke, remember
Speaker1: you told me
Speaker1: that
Speaker1: you were in
Speaker1: fear
Speaker1: for
Speaker1: your safety and that
Speaker1: you were
Speaker1: considering calling
Speaker1: the police
Speaker1: department. What
Speaker1: brought that on?
Speaker2: Oh, from that.
Speaker2: Oh, we're just
Speaker2: talking to. Yeah.
Speaker2: I, I,
Speaker2: the way he was
Speaker2: talking and,
Speaker2: and
Speaker2: yeah, honestly, I
Speaker2: felt like
Speaker2: he was going to
Speaker2: get in his car
Speaker2: and
Speaker2: drive down from
Speaker2: San Jose,
Speaker2: way
Speaker2: that he was to
Speaker1: think that,
Speaker2: you know, I'm sorry.
Speaker1: What led you
Speaker1: to think that,
Speaker2: Oh, I would say
Speaker2: just as
Speaker2: probably his tone
Speaker2: in his voice,
Speaker2: uh,
Speaker2: just,
Speaker2: you know, he was just
Speaker2: really mad
Speaker2: and
Speaker2: how T-Rock, he was
Speaker2: telling me like how
Speaker2: T-Rock is,
Speaker2: you know, they
Speaker2: discriminate and
Speaker2: the poor
Speaker2: people and
Speaker2: earlier
Speaker2: he said, well, you're a brown
Speaker2: person so you
Speaker2: understand
Speaker2: that, but
Speaker2: then he's like, but you're
Speaker2: a
Speaker2: T-Rock manager
Speaker2: too, you know?
Speaker2: And by then I just wanted
Speaker2: to get off the call
Speaker2: because
Speaker2: it
Speaker2: was the way that I
Speaker2: was just feeling, I was
Speaker2: feeling just
Speaker2: threatened by him,
Speaker2: you know? And I
Speaker2: thought,
Speaker2: man,
Speaker2: his tone of the voice,
Speaker2: I thought, geez, he's going to
Speaker2: come
Speaker2: down
Speaker2: to my house.
Speaker2: Just how I
Speaker2: felt.
Speaker2: It
Speaker2: was
Speaker2: just
Speaker2: such a horrible
Speaker2: tone.
Speaker2: It
Speaker2: was very
Speaker2: uncomfortable.
Speaker2: And that's where I started
Speaker2: feeling way
Speaker2: uncomfortable. And I've
Speaker2: never experienced this in
Speaker2: my life
Speaker2: with
Speaker2: someone just
Speaker2: so much anger
Speaker2: inside him.
Speaker2: But he never
Speaker2: physically said, I'm gonna
Speaker2: beat you up,
Speaker2: I'm
Speaker2: gonna hit
Speaker2: you. There's
Speaker2: no
Speaker2: threat like that,
Speaker2: but just his
Speaker2: tone, the way he's talking
Speaker2: to me, yeah, I felt
Speaker2: very
Speaker2: uncomfortable.
Speaker2: I did not call the
Speaker2: police, but
Speaker2: at the moment I thought,
Speaker2: geez, I kinda wanna
Speaker2: call and file
Speaker2: a complaint that I
Speaker2: have somebody
Speaker2: who's,
Speaker2: who's threatening me,
Speaker2: not that they could do
Speaker2: anything, but that's
Speaker2: how I felt
Speaker2: the moment.
Speaker2: And
Speaker2: to be honest, I felt
Speaker2: a little uncomfortable over
Speaker2: the weekend. I thought,
Speaker2: Jesus, is he
Speaker2: gonna get in his
Speaker2: car and come down
Speaker2: to my
Speaker2: house?
Speaker2: You know, he
Speaker2: didn't, of course, but,
Speaker2: um,
Speaker1: right. But I
Speaker1: guess what I'm
Speaker1: looking at,
Speaker1: right? It's because
Speaker1: I have to
Speaker1: have
Speaker1: some
Speaker1: objective
Speaker1: facts
Speaker1: that we can
Speaker1: look at. And I
Speaker1: could say,
Speaker1: Hey,
Speaker1: these are the
Speaker1: things that this
Speaker1: employee
Speaker1: did that
Speaker1: led us to
Speaker1: think that
Speaker1: he was
Speaker1: a
Speaker1: danger.
Speaker2: Right.
Speaker2: Yeah.
Speaker1: And the
Speaker1: facts that I'm looking
Speaker1: for.
Speaker2: Yeah, no. And
Speaker2: when I was talking to you,
Speaker2: Diana, you know,
Speaker2: at the time I was
Speaker2: just sharing kind of like
Speaker2: how I felt,
Speaker2: you know,
Speaker2: with
Speaker2: him calling
Speaker2: and just the tone of his
Speaker2: voice. But,
Speaker2: but yeah, I didn't,
Speaker2: you know,
Speaker2: I didn't come across
Speaker2: like, I want to file a
Speaker2: complaint to
Speaker2: T-rock and
Speaker2: say like, I feel
Speaker2: threatened by him.
Speaker2: That was just how I was
Speaker2: feeling at the moment.
Speaker2: But yeah, I mean, I don't
Speaker2: have any like
Speaker2: specifics,
Speaker2: like
Speaker2: he threatened like, you
Speaker2: know, he's going to cause like
Speaker2: any direct
Speaker2: harm.
Speaker2: He responded to
Speaker2: your email,
Speaker2: Diana, saying that I'm
Speaker2: not a violent
Speaker2: person.
Speaker2: I'm not
Speaker2: criminal. I
Speaker2: mean,
Speaker2: he didn't
Speaker2: indicate that.
Speaker2: My concern, or
Speaker2: the reason why I reached
Speaker2: out to
Speaker2: T.
Speaker2: Rock
Speaker2: was because
Speaker2: of his text
Speaker2: messages, and
Speaker2: he
Speaker2: started bombarding
Speaker2: everybody, and I
Speaker2: couldn't turn him off
Speaker2: in teams. He
Speaker2: was
Speaker2: just...
Speaker2: reaching out. And
Speaker2: so
Speaker2: my
Speaker2: concern was,
Speaker2: my main concern
Speaker2: was, I'm not sure if
Speaker2: he's
Speaker2: stable enough or
Speaker2: comfortable enough to
Speaker2: go into the stores,
Speaker2: right? Do we call
Speaker2: Costco and let him
Speaker2: know? Or I
Speaker2: didn't know how to handle that.
Speaker2: So I had reached out to
Speaker2: you,
Speaker2: Diana, because I
Speaker2: thought, I don't think you should
Speaker2: go into the store
Speaker2: because just
Speaker2: his unhappiness,
Speaker2: you know, I reached
Speaker2: out to Eric at
Speaker2: first.
Speaker2: Unfortunately, he was on
Speaker2: a call, so he couldn't
Speaker2: get ahold of me. So,
Speaker2: so that was my, that
Speaker2: was my contact
Speaker2: for T-ROC.
Speaker2: Not
Speaker2: not
Speaker2: secondary,
Speaker2: not the first,
Speaker2: because I felt
Speaker2: uncomfortable.
Speaker2: First, I was like, how do
Speaker2: we handle this? What do
Speaker2: we do? I mean,
Speaker2: sending these
Speaker2: text
Speaker2: messages and
Speaker2: unhappiness.
Speaker2: He
Speaker2: wanted me to get on the
Speaker2: phone
Speaker2: with you, Cindy,
Speaker2: when I called him on
Speaker2: Friday. He's like, I want
Speaker2: you to get on the
Speaker2: phone. I
Speaker2: want to have a three-way
Speaker2: conversation with
Speaker2: Cindy. And I
Speaker2: said,
Speaker2: I can't not
Speaker2: have a three way. I mean,
Speaker2: let me give you the
Speaker2: contact number for
Speaker2: human resources.
Speaker2: That's the way to do
Speaker2: it. And he's like,
Speaker2: no, I want you to
Speaker2: get on the
Speaker2: phone
Speaker2: because she'd lied to
Speaker2: me,
Speaker2: you know, she lied
Speaker2: to me about full time
Speaker2: job, you know.
Speaker2: And so I need to get on
Speaker2: the phone with Cindy. And I
Speaker2: said,
Speaker2: the niche I
Speaker2: cannot get on the phone a
Speaker2: three way
Speaker2: with. That's
Speaker2: not how we handle
Speaker2: things. That's just
Speaker2: not the process. So let
Speaker2: me get you a
Speaker2: human resource
Speaker2: contact number.
Speaker2: But he was
Speaker2: very adamant
Speaker2: wanting to get on the phone with
Speaker2: me and Cindy.
Speaker2: And I
Speaker2: certainly wasn't
Speaker2: going to do that.
Speaker2: So
Speaker2: Oh, there's
Speaker2: everybody.
Speaker1: Nope.
Speaker1: Oh, I'm
Speaker1: sorry. I
Speaker1: was trying
Speaker1: to talk to Rargo.
Speaker1: Here's
Speaker1: here's my
Speaker1: current
Speaker1: concern
Speaker1: based on on
Speaker1: this new
Speaker1: statement of
Speaker1: facts here.
Speaker1: When you talk
Speaker1: with Diana on
Speaker1: Friday.
Speaker1: Diana
Speaker1: told you to
Speaker1: put this
Speaker1: incident into
Speaker1: the
Speaker1: investigation
Speaker1: smart sheet
Speaker1: and we
Speaker1: would
Speaker1: handle this
Speaker1: as an employee
Speaker1: relations
Speaker1: investigation,
Speaker1: which is what it
Speaker1: is if he's
Speaker1: spamming
Speaker1: the team's
Speaker1: chat and
Speaker1: saying
Speaker1: people lied to
Speaker1: him and
Speaker1: he wants to
Speaker1: talk back to his
Speaker1: recruiter.
Speaker1: That's the
Speaker1: proper way that
Speaker1: we normally would have
Speaker1: handled
Speaker1: that.
Speaker1: In
Speaker1: response
Speaker1: to that, what
Speaker1: you told
Speaker1: Diana
Speaker1: was
Speaker1: that you were
Speaker1: afraid for your
Speaker1: safety and
Speaker1: were going to
Speaker1: call the
Speaker1: police.
Speaker1: That
Speaker1: triggers
Speaker1: an entirely
Speaker1: different
Speaker1: response
Speaker1: and caused us to
Speaker1: put this
Speaker1: employee in an
Speaker1: out
Speaker1: of work
Speaker1: status. And
Speaker1: we did so without
Speaker1: pay
Speaker1: pursuant
Speaker1: to the California
Speaker1: statute that would
Speaker1: have allowed us to
Speaker1: do that for a
Speaker1: person
Speaker1: who was
Speaker1: threatening
Speaker1: harm or
Speaker1: violence.
Speaker1: And
Speaker1: today
Speaker1: he
Speaker1: wasn't
Speaker1: doing any of those
Speaker1: things.
Speaker2: Well, I never
Speaker2: indicated to
Speaker2: Diana that.
Speaker1: No, you told her you were
Speaker1: going to, you wanted to
Speaker1: call the
Speaker1: police.
Speaker2: Yeah. Cause that's how
Speaker2: I felt.
Speaker2: Like if you, if
Speaker2: you,
Speaker2: if you talk to him
Speaker2: or, you know, if
Speaker2: you were on the phone with him,
Speaker2: yeah, I
Speaker2: felt very
Speaker2: uncomfortable. It was
Speaker2: scary.
Speaker2: So when I was
Speaker2: talking to Dana, that,
Speaker2: that was my emotional
Speaker2: reaction.
Speaker2: Um,
Speaker2: but.
Speaker2: And the reason why I
Speaker2: was calling Human
Speaker2: Resources or
Speaker2: I was calling
Speaker2: Diana for this
Speaker2: was
Speaker2: for
Speaker2: mainly, or the first
Speaker2: part of it was
Speaker2: his,
Speaker2: as you mentioned in
Speaker2: the email,
Speaker2: Diana, the
Speaker2: inflammatory,
Speaker2: discriminatory
Speaker2: and disruptive to the
Speaker2: workplace emails.
Speaker2: That was the reason why
Speaker2: I was
Speaker2: originally reaching out
Speaker2: to you guys, right?
Speaker2: Because like, here, we have a
Speaker2: situation here where
Speaker2: we have an
Speaker2: employee that is
Speaker2: sending these text
Speaker2: messages.
Speaker1: Right, and we have a
Speaker1: protocol for how
Speaker1: we handle that.
Speaker2: But it would not have
Speaker1: entailed him.
Speaker1: Okay,
Speaker1: so
Speaker1: here's what
Speaker1: we're gonna do.
Speaker2: Diana,
Speaker2: they're
Speaker2: gonna pay him
Speaker2: for
Speaker1: whatever his
Speaker1: scheduled days would
Speaker1: have been that we told
Speaker1: him he couldn't
Speaker1: work.
Speaker1: We're gonna pay him for
Speaker1: those days.
Speaker1: We are going to
Speaker1: address that he
Speaker1: has to use
Speaker1: our
Speaker1: teens
Speaker1: and
Speaker1: intranet
Speaker1: in accordance with
Speaker1: our policy, which
Speaker1: means
Speaker1: respect
Speaker1: that, you know,
Speaker1: what the policy
Speaker1: requires.
Speaker1: he needs
Speaker1: to be respectful and
Speaker1: we can
Speaker1: certainly
Speaker1: address
Speaker1: the issue of
Speaker1: respect
Speaker1: and being
Speaker1: courteous to
Speaker1: others
Speaker1: and
Speaker1: that
Speaker1: it's
Speaker1: inappropriate
Speaker1: to spam a
Speaker1: group chat with
Speaker1: messages directed to
Speaker1: particular
Speaker1: individuals that
Speaker1: he can reach out
Speaker1: directly to those
Speaker1: individuals or
Speaker1: he can
Speaker1: reach out to HR
Speaker1: and how he can
Speaker1: submit a complaint to
Speaker1: HR, but he
Speaker1: can't
Speaker1: do what he's been
Speaker1: doing.
Speaker1: But
Speaker1: I think we
Speaker1: do have
Speaker1: to
Speaker1: retract that
Speaker1: he was
Speaker1: threatening because
Speaker1: this just doesn't
Speaker1: get us to the level
Speaker1: we need to in order
Speaker1: to send him home
Speaker1: without pay
Speaker1: in California
Speaker1: under those
Speaker1: circumstances.
Speaker2: the
Speaker2: original reason I was
Speaker2: reaching out to
Speaker2: Diana was
Speaker2: because again,
Speaker2: those text
Speaker2: messages and
Speaker2: like
Speaker2: you know, because he was spending
Speaker2: everybody and he started
Speaker2: texting the group,
Speaker2: whatever, you know,
Speaker2: and I'm like, I don't think
Speaker2: he's in the right
Speaker2: mindset to go
Speaker2: to work. I
Speaker2: can even have a
Speaker2: conversation with him
Speaker2: anymore, right?
Speaker2: I think all of
Speaker2: us spoke with him.
Speaker2: Now the email you sent
Speaker2: out, Diana, which
Speaker2: to me, honestly, I
Speaker2: looked
Speaker2: at it when you sent out
Speaker2: under the, I
Speaker2: think you mentioned
Speaker2: California
Speaker2: SB553,
Speaker2: which sounds
Speaker2: to me like it's a pretty
Speaker2: serious, you
Speaker2: know, documentation
Speaker2: wise,
Speaker2: I guess it would have,
Speaker2: if I was gonna go to
Speaker2: that level,
Speaker2: then,
Speaker2: It seems like maybe
Speaker2: the
Speaker2: conversation should have
Speaker2: taken with me
Speaker2: first.
Speaker2: Well, Gerardo, let me tell you
Speaker2: exactly what
Speaker2: transpired.
Speaker2: Because when I spoke to you,
Speaker2: Danana, I was just
Speaker2: telling you how I was feeling
Speaker2: emotionally at the
Speaker2: time. I just
Speaker2: got off the phone with him. It
Speaker2: was
Speaker2: just
Speaker2: scary,
Speaker2: uncomfortable,
Speaker2: way
Speaker2: uncomfortable.
Speaker2: Well,
Speaker2: Gerardo,
Speaker1: I'm going to say
Speaker1: this.
Speaker2: Cause then I feel
Speaker2: like I'm
Speaker1: the first level
Speaker1: field manager.
Speaker1: I might
Speaker1: give you that, but
Speaker1: when someone at
Speaker1: your level
Speaker1: says things
Speaker1: like what you
Speaker1: said, that is
Speaker1: in fact going
Speaker1: to trigger a very
Speaker1: serious
Speaker1: response. And
Speaker1: you did see
Speaker1: the email. And if
Speaker1: that was not the
Speaker1: case, you
Speaker1: absolutely could
Speaker1: have said,
Speaker1: Hey,
Speaker1: hold on. I
Speaker1: think that's stronger
Speaker1: than what I wanted. And
Speaker1: I'm sure Diana
Speaker1: also told you
Speaker1: at that
Speaker1: time that she was
Speaker1: going to remove him
Speaker1: from the schedule
Speaker1: because he was being
Speaker1: threatened.
Speaker2: I don't remember the
Speaker2: exact
Speaker2: conversation. I
Speaker2: knew she was, she said she was
Speaker2: in a room, but I'm
Speaker2: like, well, yeah, she was in a
Speaker2: room because I was
Speaker2: responding with his
Speaker2: comments and it doesn't
Speaker2: seem like
Speaker2: an
Speaker2: employee who should be
Speaker2: going to work,
Speaker2: you know, by
Speaker2: all the
Speaker2: discrimination
Speaker2: emails and
Speaker2: unhappy with everybody,
Speaker2: you know,
Speaker2: slamming.
Speaker2: We don't tell
Speaker2: employees they
Speaker1: can't come to work because
Speaker1: they tell us that,
Speaker1: because they
Speaker1: complain about
Speaker1: discrimination. Cause that's
Speaker1: what you call it.
Speaker1: right
Speaker1: So no, we
Speaker1: would not have removed
Speaker1: him from the schedule
Speaker2: for that and that's not
Speaker2: a
Speaker1: basis
Speaker1: for removing
Speaker1: schedule.
Speaker1: Am I left?
Speaker1: No.
Speaker1: Diana,
Speaker1: unmute yourself, hon.
Speaker2: So you're saying with
Speaker2: all those
Speaker2: emails that he had sent
Speaker2: out, he still would
Speaker2: have been able to go to
Speaker2: work?
Speaker1: Yes, he would have been
Speaker1: able to go to work.
Speaker1: He was removed from
Speaker1: work because you
Speaker1: told her that the
Speaker1: threats were of such
Speaker1: a level and
Speaker1: quality
Speaker1: that it warranted
Speaker1: police
Speaker1: intervention.
Speaker2: I didn't tell her I
Speaker2: needed,
Speaker2: I told her how I was
Speaker2: feeling, but I didn't say
Speaker2: like,
Speaker2: anything words like,
Speaker2: oh, he's
Speaker2: gonna
Speaker2: drive
Speaker2: down and
Speaker2: cause any
Speaker2: personal harm.
Speaker2: I was just telling Diana
Speaker2: how I was feeling at the
Speaker2: time, but for me, my
Speaker2: biggest concern
Speaker2: was,
Speaker2: we can't have someone like
Speaker2: this go in the store.
Speaker2: I even told our
Speaker2: account manager, do we
Speaker2: need
Speaker2: to
Speaker2: call Costco
Speaker2: and let him
Speaker2: know?
Speaker2: you know, that we have,
Speaker2: we have an individual
Speaker2: here that is
Speaker2: extremely
Speaker2: upset who just
Speaker2: told me in
Speaker2: the chat,
Speaker2: right? If
Speaker2: there's any
Speaker2: discrimination in
Speaker2: Gerardo,
Speaker2: I'm
Speaker2: going to go
Speaker2: and I'm
Speaker2: and call
Speaker2: Bose and
Speaker2: Costco.
Speaker2: And that
Speaker2: comment,
Speaker2: that was pretty,
Speaker1: to sue
Speaker1: you and
Speaker1: report you if
Speaker1: you discriminate
Speaker1: against me, which are
Speaker1: things that he
Speaker1: has the
Speaker1: legal
Speaker1: right
Speaker1: to do.
Speaker1: And it
Speaker1: is
Speaker1: illegal
Speaker1: to take
Speaker1: adverse
Speaker1: actions against
Speaker1: him for
Speaker1: asserting
Speaker1: those
Speaker1: rights.
Speaker1: So under no
Speaker1: circumstances
Speaker1: would any member
Speaker1: of my team have
Speaker1: told you that they
Speaker1: would remove
Speaker1: him from
Speaker1: work for
Speaker1: those reasons.
Speaker1: We would have done
Speaker1: exactly what
Speaker1: Diana
Speaker1: initially told
Speaker1: you, which was
Speaker1: tell you,
Speaker1: we will start an
Speaker1: investigation
Speaker1: and get a
Speaker1: response
Speaker1: to him,
Speaker1: not
Speaker1: immediately
Speaker1: remove him from the
Speaker1: store.
Speaker1: If I sound a
Speaker1: bit
Speaker1: frustrated and
Speaker1: upset right now,
Speaker1: I am because this is
Speaker1: a big deal.
Speaker2: Oh, no,
Speaker2: I'm very
Speaker2: frustrated as well.
Speaker2: And I'm not really
Speaker2: happy right now
Speaker2: because
Speaker2: now it's being turned
Speaker2: against me.
Speaker2: Like,
Speaker2: here you have an
Speaker2: employee,
Speaker2: right,
Speaker2: who is
Speaker2: conducting himself in
Speaker2: a very appropriate
Speaker2: manner, in an
Speaker2: appropriate way.
Speaker2: I'm not a
Speaker2: manager, or I'm
Speaker2: not his direct manager.
Speaker2: Obviously I was stepping
Speaker2: in to help. He reports
Speaker2: to one of the
Speaker2: FMs,
Speaker2: right?
Speaker2: And
Speaker2: so
Speaker2: here I called Diana.
Speaker2: Hey, Diana, here we
Speaker2: have an
Speaker2: employee
Speaker2: who's,
Speaker2: you saw his emails
Speaker2: and texting
Speaker2: everybody,
Speaker2: you know,
Speaker2: trying
Speaker2: to find every
Speaker2: possible chat he was
Speaker2: in. And
Speaker2: I'm thinking, I don't
Speaker2: think he's right to go
Speaker2: into the store.
Speaker2: So when Diana
Speaker2: pulled them, I'm like, well,
Speaker2: that makes sense. Let's
Speaker2: review this and
Speaker2: be like,
Speaker2: is he right to go to the
Speaker2: store?
Speaker2: And with Dan, I shared
Speaker2: how I was feeling. Now,
Speaker2: if you are gonna send an
Speaker2: email to him and
Speaker2: say, hey,
Speaker2: California
Speaker2: SB553,
Speaker2: Then yeah, of course,
Speaker2: then I would have
Speaker2: followed up with me to
Speaker2: confirm if it's gonna
Speaker2: be this serious.
Speaker2: So
Speaker2: you're
Speaker2: frustrated,
Speaker2: and I'm very concerned
Speaker2: here with this
Speaker2: conversation.
Speaker2: How now it's
Speaker1: you're saying you didn't get
Speaker1: Diana's
Speaker1: email that told
Speaker1: you exactly
Speaker1: her basis for why
Speaker1: she did that.
Speaker1: And you didn't
Speaker1: understand
Speaker2: why
Speaker2: Diana.
Speaker2: Yeah,
Speaker2: after the fact,
Speaker2: but.
Speaker2: Yeah, this is very
Speaker2: concerning here.
Speaker1: Yeah, it is
Speaker1: extremely
Speaker2: concerning
Speaker2: here.
Speaker1: Again,
Speaker1: I just want
Speaker1: to
Speaker1: reiterate.
Speaker1: The words that
Speaker1: were sent to me on
Speaker1: Friday
Speaker1: were.
Speaker1: I'm concerned
Speaker1: for my safety.
Speaker1: At this point, I'm
Speaker1: going to
Speaker1: contact
Speaker1: San Jose
Speaker1: police
Speaker1: department
Speaker1: because I don't know
Speaker1: what this guy's
Speaker1: going to do.
Speaker1: At that point,
Speaker1: I did
Speaker1: escalate
Speaker1: it. I called Latasha
Speaker1: and I said, Latasha, this
Speaker1: is how the manager's
Speaker1: feeling.
Speaker1: Am I good to talk
Speaker1: to him and let him know
Speaker1: he's removed from the
Speaker1: schedule?
Speaker1: This is not something that
Speaker1: we take lightly.
Speaker1: So maybe the wrong
Speaker1: choice of words was
Speaker1: happened on
Speaker1: Friday,
Speaker1: but I
Speaker1: cannot.
Speaker1: stand here and
Speaker1: say, no,
Speaker1: I'm just gonna be like,
Speaker1: I'll deal with it on Monday. I
Speaker2: Yeah, I don't,
Speaker2: and
Speaker2: does Cindy have to be on
Speaker2: this call
Speaker2: now? I mean, this has
Speaker2: now gone to a different
Speaker2: level.
Speaker2: Now I'm feeling, I
Speaker2: mean, I'm
Speaker2: here thinking myself, I'm
Speaker2: like, gosh, we got this
Speaker2: employee.
Speaker1: Cindy,
Speaker2: you can drop,
Speaker1: please. Thank you.
Speaker1: Okay, thank you.
Speaker1: Just let me know if
Speaker1: you need, there are,
Speaker1: there is a lot
Speaker1: more transcripts because
Speaker1: I did talk to him a
Speaker1: lot over the course of
Speaker1: the last, because
Speaker1: he would call and check
Speaker1: in.
Speaker1: But I just sent you the
Speaker1: first and then the
Speaker1: screenshot of the
Speaker1: text where he was
Speaker1: making me feel
Speaker1: uncomfortable and I pretty
Speaker1: much stopped
Speaker1: responding.
Speaker1: Okay, and
Speaker2: you can send me
Speaker2: what you have and
Speaker2: I'll do it as
Speaker2: we are
Speaker1: going to
Speaker1: investigate the
Speaker1: conduct.
Speaker1: Yeah, I will get
Speaker1: that over to you
Speaker1: tonight. It
Speaker1: won't be till later
Speaker1: tonight. I'm heading to
Speaker1: gymnastics right now,
Speaker1: but I'll do it as soon as I
Speaker1: get back and I'll send them
Speaker1: all over.
Speaker2: All good, Cindy.
Speaker1: That's fine. That
Speaker1: sounds fun. Thank
Speaker1: you, Cindy.
Speaker1: Okay. Thank you. Bye
Speaker2: I mean, Cindy just
Speaker2: says she's, she
Speaker2: was feeling
Speaker2: uncomfortable. I think
Speaker2: that's how we were all
Speaker2: feeling. That's what I
Speaker2: felt
Speaker2: on Friday.
Speaker1: Understand there's
Speaker1: a big difference
Speaker1: between
Speaker1: uncomfortable
Speaker1: and
Speaker1: this
Speaker1: employee is
Speaker1: violating
Speaker1: our
Speaker1: workplace
Speaker1: violence
Speaker1: policy.
Speaker1: And we need to
Speaker1: call the police.
Speaker1: There's a
Speaker1: long,
Speaker1: there's a big
Speaker1: difference between
Speaker1: those things.
Speaker1: And it's a big
Speaker1: difference between the
Speaker1: employee is
Speaker1: angry
Speaker1: and,
Speaker1: and
Speaker1: Seriously,
Speaker1: as
Speaker1: you pointed out,
Speaker1: you're
Speaker1: his
Speaker1: manager's
Speaker1: manager. At
Speaker1: that
Speaker1: level,
Speaker1: some
Speaker1: expectation,
Speaker1: I guess,
Speaker1: of
Speaker1: ability to
Speaker1: separate and
Speaker1: recognize
Speaker1: that, hey, this
Speaker1: person is
Speaker1: being
Speaker1: inappropriate,
Speaker1: and they're angry, and
Speaker1: perhaps I'm not
Speaker1: able to
Speaker1: communicate with
Speaker1: them, but we do
Speaker1: need to address their
Speaker1: inappropriate
Speaker1: behavior.
Speaker1: But
Speaker1: Gerardo,
Speaker1: when you
Speaker1: They
Speaker1: were
Speaker1: like,
Speaker1: I feel like I
Speaker1: need to call
Speaker1: the police.
Speaker2: Yeah.
Speaker2: Did I say I'm going
Speaker2: to call the police?
Speaker2: No, I said,
Speaker2: I feel like I need
Speaker1: any member of my
Speaker1: team that does not
Speaker1: do what she did
Speaker1: in response to
Speaker1: someone
Speaker1: saying
Speaker1: that they feel like
Speaker1: they need to call the
Speaker1: police because they are
Speaker1: afraid of an
Speaker1: employee would be
Speaker1: unemployed
Speaker1: on Monday if they
Speaker1: did not take those
Speaker1: actions on Friday.
Speaker2: Yeah, I wish we had the caller
Speaker2: recording because, uh, Dana,
Speaker2: did I say I'm going to call
Speaker2: the police? No, I said, I
Speaker2: feel like I should
Speaker2: call the police the
Speaker2: way he's talking
Speaker1: Gerardo,
Speaker1: someone saying
Speaker1: they feel
Speaker1: like they need
Speaker1: to call the police,
Speaker1: whether you do it
Speaker1: or not,
Speaker1: personal choice.
Speaker1: Whether you
Speaker2: do it,
Speaker2: you
Speaker1: indicate that
Speaker1: this is
Speaker1: serious
Speaker1: enough for the
Speaker1: police to be
Speaker1: involved.
Speaker1: That's a
Speaker1: very serious
Speaker1: allegation that is
Speaker1: materially
Speaker1: different from
Speaker1: someone telling you,
Speaker1: I'm going to sue
Speaker1: you because
Speaker1: so
Speaker1: what?
Speaker1: Boo hoo, they're
Speaker1: gonna sue us. So
Speaker1: does everybody else
Speaker1: say that?
Speaker2: So Latasha, then
Speaker2: maybe you should have
Speaker2: called in to
Speaker2: ask these questions
Speaker2: before you send an email
Speaker2: saying,
Speaker2: and I'm looking
Speaker2: at the email that
Speaker2: report safety
Speaker2: concerns,
Speaker2: legally
Speaker2: obligated to
Speaker2: respond under
Speaker2: California
Speaker2: code,
Speaker2: the
Speaker2: 553
Speaker2: internal
Speaker2: policies.
Speaker1: Excuse you?
Speaker2: No, I'm saying then,
Speaker2: if you're going to send an
Speaker2: email like this
Speaker2: and say,
Speaker2: which now you're saying,
Speaker2: well, it's a
Speaker2: big liability for
Speaker2: T-ROC,
Speaker2: but
Speaker2: if you're going to send out an
Speaker2: email to the
Speaker2: employee and say,
Speaker2: under
Speaker2: obligation
Speaker2: response,
Speaker2: California
Speaker2: SB553,
Speaker2: the
Speaker2: employee
Speaker2: had safety
Speaker2: concerns,
Speaker2: right?
Speaker2: Then maybe
Speaker2: you should have called me to
Speaker2: make sure before we
Speaker2: send that email out
Speaker2: because my whole concern
Speaker2: wasn't.
Speaker2: So we can't
Speaker2: take.
Speaker2: Noted.
Speaker1: Okay. You know
Speaker1: what? I'm
Speaker1: Gerardo. I'm
Speaker1: not.
Speaker1: I am not
Speaker1: because you're not
Speaker1: denying that you
Speaker1: said those things to
Speaker1: Diana.
Speaker1: What you're doing
Speaker1: now is
Speaker1: going back on the
Speaker1: context.
Speaker1: And what I'm not
Speaker1: going to turn this
Speaker1: into
Speaker1: is a
Speaker1: situation
Speaker1: where
Speaker1: you think
Speaker1: that us doing
Speaker1: our jobs
Speaker1: and responding
Speaker1: to the words that you
Speaker1: say is somehow
Speaker1: inappropriate.
Speaker1: And no,
Speaker1: we
Speaker1: would
Speaker1: never.
Speaker1: make
Speaker1: someone
Speaker1: go through
Speaker1: hoops to
Speaker1: report a
Speaker1: safety issue,
Speaker1: meaning you're not going
Speaker1: to have to talk to my
Speaker1: men to an
Speaker1: HR BP,
Speaker1: then the manager
Speaker1: and then me.
Speaker1: But there is an
Speaker1: expectation
Speaker1: that,
Speaker1: that our
Speaker1: senior level
Speaker1: of managers
Speaker1: mean the
Speaker1: words that are
Speaker1: coming out of their
Speaker1: mouth in the
Speaker1: context in
Speaker1: which they say.
Speaker2: Unbelievable.
Speaker2: Yeah, I don't
Speaker2: know. Yeah, it is
Speaker1: unbelievable.
Speaker2: I think the
Speaker2: tone of
Speaker2: this conversation,
Speaker2: I'm
Speaker2: just very surprised.
Speaker2: I feel like
Speaker2: here I'm trying to
Speaker2: protect
Speaker2: the store,
Speaker2: the team,
Speaker2: this guy sending these,
Speaker2: emailing me
Speaker2: discrimination
Speaker2: emails,
Speaker2: which we all read,
Speaker2: which
Speaker2: I was happy he was out. We
Speaker2: were all like,
Speaker2: wow, he's out.
Speaker2: Cause yeah, he's
Speaker2: not ready to go to the store.
Speaker2: I couldn't even talk to him.
Speaker1: Because you told her
Speaker1: that he was a
Speaker1: threat for
Speaker1: violence.
Speaker1: And right now
Speaker1: it really
Speaker1: sounds
Speaker1: like you knew
Speaker1: that she
Speaker1: wasn't going to send
Speaker1: him home based on what
Speaker1: you told her.
Speaker1: And you came up with the
Speaker1: magic words to
Speaker1: trigger that so that
Speaker1: we would be
Speaker1: required to
Speaker1: send him home.
Speaker2: That's really what
Speaker1: it's sounding like
Speaker1: right now.
Speaker2: I'm just going to be
Speaker1: honest. That's
Speaker1: the impression I'm
Speaker1: getting. And
Speaker1: especially
Speaker2: now that you want to
Speaker2: throw it
Speaker1: back and hold on
Speaker1: now.
Speaker1: that you want
Speaker1: to deflect back
Speaker1: and try to say that
Speaker1: somehow
Speaker1: we should have
Speaker1: followed up with you
Speaker1: to see if you really
Speaker1: meant what you
Speaker1: told us
Speaker1: the first time.
Speaker1: Make it make
Speaker1: sense.
Speaker2: Wait, so you're
Speaker2: saying that I
Speaker2: said that I didn't
Speaker2: think
Speaker2: his
Speaker2: email
Speaker2: wasn't sufficient enough
Speaker2: to send him
Speaker2: home.
Speaker2: So you said that I
Speaker2: decided-
Speaker2: Diana told
Speaker1: you it was not,
Speaker1: Diana told
Speaker1: you to
Speaker1: put that on the
Speaker1: smart sheet
Speaker1: for an
Speaker1: investigation
Speaker1: and we would have done an
Speaker1: employee relations
Speaker1: investigation.
Speaker1: That's what she
Speaker1: instructed
Speaker1: you to do.
Speaker2: instructed- I didn't want to
Speaker2: be clear where you just said
Speaker2: LaTosha, because that's
Speaker2: huge. And
Speaker2: Jerry and Dinah, you're
Speaker2: on the call.
Speaker2: You just said that
Speaker2: by his tone of
Speaker2: language, it wasn't going to
Speaker2: be enough
Speaker2: to send them home,
Speaker2: so then I made
Speaker2: up and
Speaker2: came up
Speaker2: with the thing that he-
Speaker2: I'm saying that the
Speaker2: sequence
Speaker1: of facts
Speaker1: and
Speaker1: hear
Speaker1: me,
Speaker1: we can
Speaker1: investigate that if
Speaker1: you prefer, but I'm
Speaker1: saying that the
Speaker1: sequence of
Speaker1: events
Speaker1: just does not,
Speaker1: this context,
Speaker1: Gerardo, just really
Speaker1: doesn't look
Speaker1: good.
Speaker1: And
Speaker1: especially
Speaker2: when,
Speaker2: because you're not
Speaker1: standing, you're
Speaker1: not standing by
Speaker1: what you said
Speaker1: to Diana on
Speaker1: Friday.
Speaker1: And now
Speaker1: there's a walk
Speaker1: back to the
Speaker1: severity of
Speaker1: what
Speaker1: happened when
Speaker1: we say, Hey,
Speaker1: give me
Speaker1: facts.
Speaker1: I
Speaker1: came on here
Speaker1: because I
Speaker1: was preparing to
Speaker1: call the employee to
Speaker1: say, yeah,
Speaker1: here, these are the
Speaker1: reasons why we
Speaker1: said you were
Speaker1: violent and could
Speaker1: not be in the
Speaker1: workplace. Because
Speaker1: that's what that
Speaker1: notice in
Speaker1: essence said to
Speaker1: him.
Speaker1: When you got that
Speaker1: email on
Speaker1: Friday
Speaker1: that
Speaker1: At
Speaker1: that, if
Speaker1: that was not the
Speaker1: case, you
Speaker1: absolutely could have
Speaker1: followed him and said, hey,
Speaker1: hold on, Diana.
Speaker1: I wasn't
Speaker1: invoking
Speaker1: a
Speaker1: workplace
Speaker1: violence
Speaker1: act against
Speaker1: the employee.
Speaker1: This is what was
Speaker1: really going on.
Speaker1: You didn't do
Speaker1: that.
Speaker1: And to now
Speaker1: imply
Speaker1: that there is
Speaker1: somehow something
Speaker1: wrong with
Speaker1: people
Speaker1: experiencing
Speaker1: this process,
Speaker1: because we didn't call
Speaker1: you back and ask you
Speaker1: if you were really
Speaker1: sure that
Speaker1: you meant you were
Speaker1: scared enough to
Speaker1: call the police.
Speaker2: So again,
Speaker1: that's,
Speaker1: that's, that's
Speaker1: not,
Speaker2: so, so
Speaker2: again, I just want
Speaker2: to make
Speaker1: sure this is
Speaker2: really big though.
Speaker2: You're saying
Speaker2: that, that I didn't think
Speaker2: it was enough
Speaker2: that you hadn't
Speaker2: removed. So you said that
Speaker2: I may up
Speaker2: the threat.
Speaker1: Well, what I'm saying
Speaker1: is
Speaker2: what you said to her
Speaker1: on Friday is not
Speaker1: what you're saying to
Speaker1: me on Monday.
Speaker1: And you're right. I
Speaker1: don't know why
Speaker1: that is,
Speaker1: but it
Speaker1: concerning that
Speaker1: that's
Speaker1: huge
Speaker1: inconsistency
Speaker1: and it is
Speaker1: glaring.
Speaker1: And
Speaker1: especially
Speaker1: glaring in light of the
Speaker1: fact that you are
Speaker1: attempting to
Speaker1: deflect it back
Speaker1: and say that
Speaker1: somehow people
Speaker1: experience should have
Speaker1: asked you
Speaker1: if is
Speaker1: really meant is
Speaker1: and if scared
Speaker1: really meant
Speaker1: scared.
Speaker2: No, I was
Speaker2: saying that if
Speaker2: you think it's a
Speaker2: concern that the,
Speaker2: you know, issuing a
Speaker2: California SB
Speaker2: 553 if it's
Speaker2: that serious
Speaker2: before you send it out.
Speaker2: That's what I'm saying like.
Speaker1: Yeah,
Speaker2: this conversation would
Speaker2: happen way
Speaker2: before that was sent out
Speaker2: then. Because
Speaker2: you know more of the
Speaker2: seriousness of that
Speaker2: than I do as far as
Speaker2: HR
Speaker2: laws. I don't
Speaker2: know,
Speaker2: sending that out to an
Speaker2: employee, what does
Speaker2: that mean
Speaker2: legally? That's
Speaker2: not my
Speaker2: expertise. I don't know
Speaker2: anything about that.
Speaker2: there's
Speaker2: consequences
Speaker2: obviously, there's
Speaker2: liability issues
Speaker2: now if you're sending a
Speaker2: rep home without paying on the
Speaker2: state of California, which
Speaker2: I understand the living
Speaker2: California.
Speaker2: But to me,
Speaker2: it's just very
Speaker2: concerning that
Speaker2: you're telling
Speaker2: me that I made it
Speaker2: up,
Speaker2: that
Speaker2: Diana was not
Speaker2: gonna send him home
Speaker2: because that wasn't enough.
Speaker2: So then I made
Speaker2: up,
Speaker2: but the whole like he
Speaker2: threatened
Speaker2: me so
Speaker2: that way he can go,
Speaker2: he
Speaker2: can get pushed out of the
Speaker2: store. Like to me, that's
Speaker2: just-
Speaker1: I'm gonna put it to
Speaker1: you this way.
Speaker1: Can I
Speaker1: prove that
Speaker1: that's why you
Speaker1: did it?
Speaker1: No.
Speaker1: What I can
Speaker1: say though,
Speaker1: Gerardo,
Speaker1: is I'm
Speaker1: very,
Speaker1: very
Speaker1: disappointed
Speaker1: it with
Speaker1: this series of
Speaker1: events and the way
Speaker1: this transpire.
Speaker2: Well, I'm just want
Speaker2: to help hold this.
Speaker2: Yeah. How this
Speaker2: has all turned
Speaker2: out.
Speaker1: And I'm really
Speaker1: disappointed
Speaker1: that
Speaker1: although you,
Speaker1: you know what?
Speaker2: Yeah, I
Speaker2: think we need a
Speaker2: conversation. I
Speaker2: need to talk to my
Speaker2: manager.
Speaker1: This was done.
Speaker1: Understand
Speaker1: that we're
Speaker1: going to
Speaker1: support
Speaker2: I
Speaker2: feel no
Speaker2: support
Speaker1: here.
Speaker1: Any employee of
Speaker1: ours that
Speaker1: says that they are
Speaker1: in fear for their
Speaker1: safety,
Speaker1: we are going
Speaker1: to go
Speaker1: above
Speaker1: and beyond. And
Speaker1: we are going to
Speaker1: take
Speaker1: immediate,
Speaker1: immediate
Speaker1: action,
Speaker1: which is
Speaker1: exactly
Speaker1: what
Speaker1: Diana did.
Speaker1: And that's
Speaker1: exactly
Speaker1: what
Speaker1: we
Speaker1: expect
Speaker1: and what every
Speaker1: employee is
Speaker1: entitled
Speaker1: to.
Speaker1: In return
Speaker1: for that though,
Speaker1: there's
Speaker1: a level of
Speaker1: trust
Speaker1: in what the
Speaker1: employees are
Speaker1: reporting to
Speaker1: us.
Speaker1: especially
Speaker1: when it
Speaker1: is
Speaker1: someone
Speaker1: at a
Speaker1: senior
Speaker1: level of
Speaker1: management,
Speaker1: the
Speaker1: credibility
Speaker1: is
Speaker1: very
Speaker1: important. Like I
Speaker1: can't
Speaker1: overstate how
Speaker1: important it
Speaker1: is
Speaker1: were told
Speaker1: truthful
Speaker2: and factual information. I told
Speaker2: then how I felt.
Speaker2: I didn't make
Speaker2: anything up.
Speaker2: Like
Speaker2: I've been doing this as
Speaker2: many, I've
Speaker2: been in this
Speaker2: field for 15, 20
Speaker2: years. Do you think that
Speaker2: I'm sitting here just
Speaker2: making things up or
Speaker2: just?
Speaker1: You've been in the field 15,
Speaker1: 20 years and
Speaker1: you've never had an
Speaker1: employee angry
Speaker1: at you?
Speaker2: Yeah, not this
Speaker2: level.
Speaker2: Not this level at
Speaker2: all, no.
Speaker2: And I've been very proud with
Speaker2: my record. I've never
Speaker2: had really
Speaker2: any issues
Speaker2: with
Speaker2: employees or
Speaker2: interacting
Speaker2: with them because every
Speaker2: time with every
Speaker2: employee that I've worked,
Speaker2: every field rep that
Speaker2: I've had in the last 15,
Speaker2: 20 years, I
Speaker2: always build good,
Speaker2: solid relationships
Speaker2: with them
Speaker2: and work with them, have
Speaker2: success with them.
Speaker2: And that's something I always
Speaker2: taught with my record
Speaker2: as being an
Speaker2: employee when I was
Speaker2: a field manager,
Speaker2: never
Speaker2: had any issues with
Speaker2: employees. Sure, they
Speaker2: get mad and get
Speaker2: paid,
Speaker2: but this
Speaker2: rep on
Speaker2: Friday, on
Speaker2: Thursday, oh my
Speaker2: gosh, I've
Speaker2: never in my
Speaker2: life
Speaker2: had a rep
Speaker2: with so much
Speaker2: anger
Speaker2: in his
Speaker2: text messages,
Speaker2: where I could even talk to
Speaker2: him.
Speaker2: I told Dan, I'm like, I
Speaker2: can't call. It's
Speaker2: impossible to talk to the
Speaker2: guy. I
Speaker2: mean, maybe you
Speaker2: guys have success,
Speaker2: but
Speaker2: I mean, he was just
Speaker2: mad. And
Speaker2: he still
Speaker2: texted me this
Speaker2: morning,
Speaker2: which I forwarded you
Speaker2: guys, which I'm not gonna
Speaker2: reply back to him.
Speaker2: He sent me more
Speaker2: messages this
Speaker2: morning, right?
Speaker2: He called my
Speaker2: voicemail. He
Speaker2: left me a voicemail.
Speaker2: He wants me to call him
Speaker2: back.
Speaker2: And then he sent me
Speaker2: another text
Speaker2: message this
Speaker2: afternoon
Speaker2: or this
Speaker2: morning, you know,
Speaker2: and I did not reply
Speaker2: back.
Speaker2: I think he called me a few
Speaker2: times this morning.
Speaker2: And I'm not gonna call him
Speaker2: back.
Speaker2: I'm not gonna make it worse
Speaker2: for him, for
Speaker2: me, or for all of
Speaker2: us,
Speaker2: you know.
Speaker2: And I should listen, I
Speaker2: listened to voicemail, then
Speaker2: I stopped.
Speaker2: He went back to
Speaker2: the same thing
Speaker2: again.
Speaker2: You need to call me
Speaker2: back. And so
Speaker2: what did I do? I emailed
Speaker2: Diana. Diana,
Speaker2: he wants someone to
Speaker2: call him because he wants to get
Speaker2: paid.
Speaker2: And so that's where you left me
Speaker2: the message this morning
Speaker2: saying, Gerardo, you need
Speaker2: to pay me. I
Speaker2: have it on the recording
Speaker2: here. I'll send it to you
Speaker2: if you want,
Speaker2: asking to get
Speaker2: paid. He sent me an
Speaker2: email as
Speaker2: well, which I copied and
Speaker2: pasted and I sent it to
Speaker2: Diana.
Speaker2: Can someone please
Speaker2: call him because he
Speaker2: wants to get paid, which he's
Speaker2: not going to get paid.
Speaker2: I mean, yeah,
Speaker2: he
Speaker1: is.
Speaker1: He
Speaker1: absolutely is.
Speaker2: Well, yeah, but he wanted to get paid
Speaker2: now, now, now.
Speaker1: No, it won't
Speaker1: be
Speaker1: today,
Speaker1: but yes, he's
Speaker1: absolutely going to be
Speaker1: paid.
Speaker2: Oh yeah. I
Speaker2: mean, yeah,
Speaker2: he's, he's paid for work
Speaker2: from last week and then he
Speaker2: did.
Speaker1: Okay.
Speaker1: Diana
Speaker1: submit
Speaker1: the pay
Speaker1: adjustment.
Speaker1: Thank you, ma'am. I'm
Speaker1: going to put a call
Speaker1: on his calendar so we
Speaker1: could speak to him
Speaker1: tomorrow. Yes,
Speaker1: please. And
Speaker1: find out
Speaker1: what days he
Speaker1: was supposed to
Speaker1: work that we told him
Speaker1: he couldn't work
Speaker1: so that we can
Speaker1: make the adjustment for
Speaker1: those days.
Speaker1: And then
Speaker1: let's just
Speaker1: do the
Speaker1: investigation
Speaker1: for the
Speaker1: improper
Speaker1: communications,
Speaker1: please, ma'am.
Speaker2: OK.
Speaker2: All right.
Speaker2: So if he's going to be
Speaker2: allowed to
Speaker2: return,
Speaker2: Please include
Speaker2: Eric Schulte
Speaker2: and Chris, I
Speaker2: mean.
Speaker1: I
Speaker1: absolutely
Speaker1: will.
Speaker2: Because
Speaker2: I can
Speaker2: tell you right now, there's no way
Speaker2: in the world he's gonna come
Speaker2: back and be able to
Speaker2: handle himself and
Speaker2: work in a professional
Speaker2: manner. I can
Speaker2: tell you that right now.
Speaker2: There's no way. Then if he
Speaker1: acts up in the
Speaker1: store and he's
Speaker1: unprofessional,
Speaker1: then you can
Speaker1: absolutely
Speaker1: deal with it
Speaker1: then. But
Speaker1: you
Speaker1: absolutely
Speaker1: can't tell
Speaker1: somebody they can't
Speaker1: come to work just
Speaker1: because they tell you
Speaker1: they're gonna sue you for
Speaker1: discrimination.
Speaker1: Not going to
Speaker1: happen.
Speaker2: And I didn't tell him
Speaker2: because of that. And
Speaker1: I'm telling you,
Speaker1: we can't
Speaker1: either.
Speaker2: The reason I contact
Speaker2: Diana was because
Speaker2: how he was
Speaker2: blasting the
Speaker2: team.
Speaker2: Correct. The
Speaker2: reason why I call
Speaker2: and how do we handle
Speaker2: this?
Speaker1: And she's
Speaker1: going to do
Speaker1: exactly what
Speaker1: she told you. And what
Speaker1: I just told you
Speaker1: is we
Speaker1: will in fact
Speaker1: investigate.
Speaker1: And if
Speaker1: warranted
Speaker1: corrective action
Speaker1: will be
Speaker1: recommended
Speaker1: based on the
Speaker1: behavior he's
Speaker1: actually
Speaker1: exhibiting,
Speaker1: which is the
Speaker1: blasting the
Speaker1: messages. And in
Speaker1: fact, we'll attempt to
Speaker1: clarify with him,
Speaker1: Hey, we've looked
Speaker1: at the cost from your
Speaker1: recruiter. Here's what
Speaker1: your recruiter told
Speaker1: you.
Speaker2: And if,
Speaker2: if, if, if T
Speaker2: rock makes the
Speaker2: decision,
Speaker2: Latasha,
Speaker2: you know, we
Speaker2: talked to
Speaker2: Gerardo.
Speaker2: don't conclude
Speaker2: that it was a threat,
Speaker2: then that's fine.
Speaker2: I'm okay with
Speaker2: that, because that
Speaker2: wasn't my main reason
Speaker2: of calling
Speaker2: Diana. It was
Speaker2: calling because
Speaker2: his
Speaker2: emails and
Speaker2: blasting
Speaker2: the
Speaker2: team
Speaker2: and
Speaker2: all this
Speaker2: racist stuff
Speaker2: about the white
Speaker2: person.
Speaker2: I'm
Speaker2: like,
Speaker2: yeah,
Speaker2: I'm fine with that. Now,
Speaker2: if you conclude while I'm
Speaker2: thinking- Yeah, he
Speaker1: said we were racist and we were
Speaker1: discriminating
Speaker1: against him and we were
Speaker1: keeping brown and
Speaker1: black people
Speaker1: poor.
Speaker1: Yeah, I
Speaker1: saw that.
Speaker2: And he told me that too. And
Speaker2: I said,
Speaker2: Natasha,
Speaker2: I understand, I
Speaker2: get it.
Speaker2: He said, his mom is
Speaker2: sick.
Speaker2: I said,
Speaker2: my mom is sick too.
Speaker2: She's 85, I
Speaker2: get it. But I
Speaker2: can't fix that.
Speaker2: Our
Speaker2: focus is the
Speaker2: program. This is a
Speaker2: short six-week
Speaker2: program. We're trying
Speaker2: to
Speaker2: get more work from
Speaker2: Bose. I've been
Speaker2: working on the Bose
Speaker2: program for three
Speaker2: years. So
Speaker2: I
Speaker2: said, that's the focus.
Speaker2: I wanted him to get,
Speaker2: that's the focus. And
Speaker2: then it just did
Speaker2: not even work at all.
Speaker2: And I
Speaker2: said, okay, well, I
Speaker2: tried.
Speaker2: calm them down,
Speaker2: you know?
Speaker2: And
Speaker2: then the
Speaker2: barrage of taxes
Speaker2: started happening. Then
Speaker2: Chris, my partner
Speaker2: account, he's like, what do we
Speaker2: do? I said, well, I called
Speaker2: Eric, he's not
Speaker2: answering. So
Speaker2: Eric did say, well, call
Speaker2: Dan, okay, Diana,
Speaker2: here's the issue,
Speaker2: you know? And I
Speaker2: had just got off the phone
Speaker2: with him
Speaker2: and I
Speaker2: shared with Diana how
Speaker2: I was
Speaker2: feeling at
Speaker2: the moment.
Speaker2: Because that's what I
Speaker2: felt.
Speaker2: So if you
Speaker2: concluded,
Speaker2: and
Speaker2: I respected, like,
Speaker2: you know what, I don't think
Speaker2: it was threatening, then
Speaker2: okay, fine,
Speaker2: I'm okay
Speaker2: with that. That's
Speaker2: not my concern. My making
Speaker2: concern, is he gonna go back
Speaker2: to the store?
Speaker2: On a personal level,
Speaker2: yes. On a
Speaker2: personal level, of
Speaker2: course. You
Speaker2: know, I've got my family
Speaker2: here. I have this
Speaker2: person who's just
Speaker2: very frustrated,
Speaker2: mad, anger,
Speaker2: you know,
Speaker2: mad at the world,
Speaker2: mad at me.
Speaker2: Yeah, of course,
Speaker2: I'm gonna feel the way.
Speaker2: I'm human, and
Speaker2: that's what I felt
Speaker2: on
Speaker2: Friday.
Speaker2: for the safety of me and my
Speaker2: family. Of course,
Speaker2: everything runs
Speaker2: through your head in
Speaker2: today's
Speaker2: society. But if
Speaker2: T-ROC says, no, we
Speaker2: don't feel like there's any
Speaker2: threat, then that's fine.
Speaker2: I'm
Speaker2: okay
Speaker2: with
Speaker2: that.
Speaker2: That's
Speaker2: your investigation. You
Speaker2: know how to do this. This is
Speaker2: your job. But
Speaker2: I just wanna
Speaker2: be clear,
Speaker2: Latasha, I would
Speaker2: never, in
Speaker2: my career
Speaker2: ever,
Speaker2: come up with something
Speaker2: and say, well, if
Speaker2: his
Speaker2: discrimination is not
Speaker2: enough or
Speaker2: his comments are not enough
Speaker2: to get
Speaker2: removed
Speaker2: from the program, well, let
Speaker2: me throw in that I
Speaker2: felt violent.
Speaker2: I felt violence
Speaker2: towards me. Maybe
Speaker2: without getting removed
Speaker2: from the store.
Speaker2: No, I
Speaker2: would never do
Speaker2: that.
Speaker2: And if that's how you
Speaker2: feel, then that's how
Speaker2: you feel. But that's
Speaker2: just, I would
Speaker2: never do that.
Speaker2: Never, never do
Speaker2: that. And
Speaker2: that's concerning
Speaker2: to me,
Speaker2: but
Speaker2: it is what it is.
Speaker1: Well, it,
Speaker1: like I said, it's
Speaker1: concerning because
Speaker1: it feels like the,
Speaker1: the threatening
Speaker1: part of it
Speaker1: was made up.
Speaker1: That's all I'm
Speaker1: saying.
Speaker2: Oh, now it's made
Speaker2: up. Oh, now
Speaker2: so made up now.
Speaker1: I don't know why,
Speaker1: but I
Speaker1: can't,
Speaker1: it's not based
Speaker1: on any
Speaker1: objective
Speaker1: facts that you
Speaker1: were able to convey
Speaker1: to us. How's
Speaker1: that?
Speaker2: So it's
Speaker2: objective
Speaker2: facts.
Speaker2: Okay. Not always
Speaker2: feeling
Speaker2: cause you didn't, you weren't there
Speaker2: with me, but
Speaker1: Well, if we
Speaker1: feel a way,
Speaker1: right? The
Speaker1: feelings are
Speaker1: based on something
Speaker1: factually that
Speaker1: happened. And so
Speaker1: I've asked you
Speaker1: what factually
Speaker1: happened
Speaker2: that led you to feel
Speaker2: that way.
Speaker2: So feelings have to be
Speaker2: fact.
Speaker2: It's not how I'm feeling
Speaker2: personally.
Speaker1: No,
Speaker1: how you feel
Speaker1: personally is
Speaker1: based on a
Speaker1: series of facts
Speaker1: that occur. And I
Speaker1: asked you
Speaker1: share
Speaker1: the facts that
Speaker1: happened
Speaker1: that made you
Speaker1: feel
Speaker1: unsafe.
Speaker1: What happened to
Speaker1: you that caused
Speaker1: you to
Speaker1: feel the way you
Speaker1: felt?
Speaker2: And that's what I felt.
Speaker2: And now I have T-Rock
Speaker2: coming back to me
Speaker2: saying, nope,
Speaker2: you shouldn't have felt that
Speaker2: way.
Speaker1: No, I'm telling
Speaker1: you, because you
Speaker1: told me you
Speaker1: could not come up
Speaker1: with a reason.
Speaker1: But you know
Speaker1: what?
Speaker1: It's fine.
Speaker1: It's
Speaker2: fine.
Speaker2: So that's
Speaker2: what I felt.
Speaker2: And now T-Rock
Speaker2: saying, well,
Speaker2: nope,
Speaker2: you
Speaker2: how you felt was in
Speaker2: facts, and now
Speaker2: that's concerning.
Speaker2: And
Speaker2: you're concerned,
Speaker2: because I'm not a
Speaker2: senior executive, I
Speaker2: wish I was,
Speaker2: senior manager
Speaker2: or senior executive.
Speaker2: said senior
Speaker1: manager. I
Speaker2: gotta be more
Speaker2: careful with my
Speaker2: words on
Speaker2: how it's feeling, but
Speaker2: you're saying, nope, I
Speaker2: don't think it was feeling,
Speaker2: so I think you made it
Speaker2: up.
Speaker2: And so now
Speaker2: you're saying like, this
Speaker2: looks bad.
Speaker2: Like, I just, I'm
Speaker2: just,
Speaker2: I'm...
Speaker1: No, and what I'm
Speaker1: saying is
Speaker1: when I come
Speaker1: and say,
Speaker1: okay, tell me
Speaker1: what he said
Speaker1: and what he did
Speaker1: that was
Speaker1: threatening.
Speaker1: And
Speaker1: maybe
Speaker1: my
Speaker1: expectation
Speaker1: of what
Speaker1: you would
Speaker1: convey
Speaker1: as
Speaker1: being
Speaker1: threatening
Speaker1: to you,
Speaker1: like I would
Speaker1: never, okay, I'm gonna
Speaker1: put it this way,
Speaker1: reporting that
Speaker1: someone
Speaker1: that you work
Speaker1: with
Speaker1: Threatening you
Speaker1: is a
Speaker1: very serious
Speaker1: allegation.
Speaker1: And
Speaker2: I would never
Speaker1: make that
Speaker1: without
Speaker1: being able to
Speaker1: say,
Speaker1: Hey,
Speaker1: he told me
Speaker1: if I don't
Speaker1: have his money,
Speaker1: he's going to bust me
Speaker1: upside my head.
Speaker1: Or he said, I'm
Speaker1: getting in my car
Speaker1: right now
Speaker1: and I'm heading up
Speaker1: there.
Speaker1: and you will
Speaker1: do,
Speaker1: like, that's the
Speaker1: kind of thing
Speaker1: that I
Speaker1: was looking for
Speaker1: when you report
Speaker1: to HR
Speaker1: that somebody's
Speaker1: threatening you and
Speaker1: you're afraid of them
Speaker1: and you need to call the
Speaker1: police.
Speaker2: Yeah, that's how I was
Speaker2: feeling though.
Speaker2: I didn't call the
Speaker2: police. I
Speaker2: told Dana,
Speaker2: I feel like I should have called
Speaker2: the police. I didn't say I
Speaker2: wanted to call the police.
Speaker2: I never did call the
Speaker2: police. But
Speaker2: yeah, that's how I
Speaker2: was feeling.
Speaker2: Here's an
Speaker2: individual, and if
Speaker2: you spoke to him, and
Speaker2: I'm sure you've talked to him,
Speaker2: or Dan, and
Speaker2: you've probably talked to him,
Speaker2: yeah.
Speaker2: Listening to
Speaker2: him,
Speaker2: yeah, that's how I
Speaker2: felt.
Speaker2: And if you've
Speaker2: concluded,
Speaker2: like, you know
Speaker2: what, like for,
Speaker2: like, I
Speaker2: get it,
Speaker2: Latasha, for
Speaker2: legality, like,
Speaker2: you have to make the
Speaker2: decision because,
Speaker2: like, if you had to go
Speaker2: in a court of law,
Speaker2: right,
Speaker2: you have to present,
Speaker2: like, here's
Speaker2: Gerardo,
Speaker2: this is how he's felt,
Speaker2: right? And if you feel like, you
Speaker2: know what, there's
Speaker2: nothing that you're
Speaker2: saying to me
Speaker2: that
Speaker2: makes it, you
Speaker2: know, in the court of
Speaker2: law, whatever those
Speaker2: laws might be, I
Speaker2: get that.
Speaker2: But I would, I
Speaker2: feel like at least
Speaker2: some
Speaker2: understanding from
Speaker2: T-ROC, like,
Speaker2: hey, we
Speaker2: understanding you
Speaker2: feeling,
Speaker2: it doesn't
Speaker2: reach that level we
Speaker2: think, we can't
Speaker2: prove that in a court of law,
Speaker2: because this is what at the end of
Speaker2: the day,
Speaker2: you know,
Speaker2: okay,
Speaker2: it's fine. I
Speaker2: mean,
Speaker2: It's not like you're gonna
Speaker2: go get
Speaker2: security guards
Speaker2: coming by.
Speaker2: T-ROD's not gonna do
Speaker2: anything different if
Speaker2: he was,
Speaker2: you
Speaker2: know, if
Speaker2: he was to feel
Speaker2: threatened. So if
Speaker2: you feel like, you know what,
Speaker2: Gerardo, there's really
Speaker2: nothing legally
Speaker2: wise that we can hold in
Speaker2: court, fine.
Speaker2: No
Speaker2: worries, I get
Speaker2: that. It's not like
Speaker2: this is my first
Speaker2: rodeo.
Speaker2: But I don't feel there's
Speaker2: anything wrong with
Speaker2: me sharing how I
Speaker2: felt, but
Speaker2: it's just kind of a
Speaker2: bummer that
Speaker2: now T-rock is
Speaker2: coming at me saying
Speaker2: that I'm
Speaker2: wrong, they're
Speaker2: disappointed in
Speaker2: me,
Speaker2: like
Speaker2: your
Speaker2: feelings weren't
Speaker2: facts,
Speaker2: like...
Speaker1: You're
Speaker1: entitled to
Speaker1: your feelings,
Speaker1: but understand,
Speaker1: Gerardo, that when
Speaker1: you
Speaker1: report
Speaker1: it
Speaker1: to
Speaker1: us,
Speaker1: you're not telling your
Speaker1: therapist how you
Speaker1: felt. You're telling
Speaker1: us you want us to
Speaker1: take action against
Speaker1: another
Speaker1: employee. And
Speaker1: that's a different
Speaker1: standard.
Speaker2: That's a legal
Speaker2: standard. I didn't
Speaker2: say to take action
Speaker2: because he was being
Speaker2: violent.
Speaker2: The reason why I called
Speaker2: Diana was because
Speaker2: of his texting. I didn't
Speaker2: know how to stop
Speaker2: that.
Speaker2: Eric's like,
Speaker2: contact
Speaker2: Lucas, and
Speaker2: Lucas, I can't delete
Speaker2: it. I'm like,
Speaker2: okay, fine.
Speaker2: That is the reason why I
Speaker2: originally called
Speaker2: Diana, was
Speaker2: Diana, we have a
Speaker2: rep who's just going
Speaker2: off the rails here,
Speaker2: he's
Speaker2: already sending,
Speaker2: and talk to
Speaker2: Mikkel,
Speaker2: who also manages him,
Speaker2: he had the same
Speaker2: experience with him.
Speaker2: told him to submit a
Speaker2: report,
Speaker2: but that's
Speaker2: how I felt. But yeah, I
Speaker2: know no in
Speaker2: time that I said,
Speaker2: well, I gotta get him
Speaker2: out of here. I'm gonna throw in,
Speaker2: you know, fear
Speaker2: or like he's being
Speaker2: threatening to get him out.
Speaker2: Cause that's
Speaker2: the,
Speaker2: Oh,
Speaker2: but I just shared
Speaker2: it. I
Speaker2: was feeling
Speaker2: that's all.
Speaker1: I don't think, I
Speaker1: don't, I think,
Speaker1: I think that
Speaker1: what,
Speaker1: what
Speaker1: isn't clear here
Speaker1: is I completely
Speaker1: understood
Speaker1: what
Speaker1: your complaint was
Speaker1: originally.
Speaker1: Your complaint was
Speaker1: that he,
Speaker1: was doing
Speaker1: a lot in teams and
Speaker1: you wanted to get it
Speaker1: removed and
Speaker1: you didn't really want him
Speaker1: working because,
Speaker1: you know,
Speaker1: he was not,
Speaker1: you didn't feel like he was
Speaker1: stable. I got
Speaker1: that. I
Speaker1: completely understood
Speaker1: that. And I
Speaker1: did say, you know,
Speaker1: Gerardo, go ahead and put an
Speaker1: investigation, smart
Speaker1: sheet,
Speaker1: put it, include all the
Speaker1: screenshots, include
Speaker1: everything.
Speaker1: We were fine up until
Speaker1: that point. But then
Speaker1: when you said
Speaker1: that
Speaker1: saying, I know, you know, I don't
Speaker1: know at this point, I don't know
Speaker1: what this guy's going to do.
Speaker1: I,
Speaker2: I was sharing with
Speaker2: you like.
Speaker1: No, and I get
Speaker1: that, but but you
Speaker1: know,
Speaker1: yes,
Speaker1: but it's not really
Speaker1: just talking when you're
Speaker1: speaking to someone
Speaker1: who's
Speaker1: in HR.
Speaker1: If I feel like
Speaker1: you're you're getting
Speaker1: this off your chest, like I
Speaker1: don't think he's stable.
Speaker1: I feel like I
Speaker1: need to call the police. I
Speaker1: don't know what he's
Speaker1: capable of. At that
Speaker1: point,
Speaker1: you're fearing for your
Speaker1: safety, whether
Speaker1: that's what you
Speaker1: intended to tell
Speaker1: me or not.
Speaker1: Right. And that's
Speaker1: all that's all it's all
Speaker1: she's saying.
Speaker1: You saying that
Speaker1: statement to me is
Speaker1: what made
Speaker1: me
Speaker1: react and
Speaker1: go ahead and remove
Speaker1: him from the schedule. It
Speaker1: was not about
Speaker1: the messages.
Speaker2: why I decided to
Speaker2: tell for your life.
Speaker2: Like when you know,
Speaker2: but
Speaker2: I told you to put it on, I
Speaker1: told you to put it
Speaker1: on. No,
Speaker2: I told you to put him on.
Speaker2: I'm
Speaker2: like, you're gonna
Speaker2: investigate his
Speaker2: chats. I'm like,
Speaker2: that makes
Speaker2: totally mistakes.
Speaker2: I've been,
Speaker2: that made sense to me. I'm
Speaker2: like, oh,
Speaker2: I'm pulling off the program.
Speaker2: Like, yeah, you guys, you're
Speaker2: gonna investigate his
Speaker2: unhappiness. Should be
Speaker2: working at T-ROC. He
Speaker2: doesn't seem happy at
Speaker2: all. Like
Speaker2: to me, that seemed
Speaker2: fair.
Speaker1: But did you
Speaker1: see how our
Speaker1: conversation went?
Speaker1: You just agreed with me
Speaker1: to every point that I
Speaker1: said, we had
Speaker1: this conversation.
Speaker1: I said this.
Speaker1: I told you put on the
Speaker1: investigation.
Speaker1: It wasn't until
Speaker1: you
Speaker1: told me
Speaker1: that you felt
Speaker1: that you needed to call the
Speaker1: police that I said, well, then
Speaker1: in that case,
Speaker1: I'm just going to remove
Speaker1: him. I
Speaker1: will call him now.
Speaker1: Remember?
Speaker2: No,
Speaker2: I didn't get no clear
Speaker2: indication that there
Speaker2: isn't a way you're going to
Speaker2: remove him from the store
Speaker2: because
Speaker1: I told you that I was
Speaker2: going to call him
Speaker1: and speak to
Speaker1: him.
Speaker1: The email
Speaker1: that I
Speaker1: sent out
Speaker1: was after I spoke
Speaker1: to him. I did tell you
Speaker1: that. You told me you
Speaker1: didn't want to speak to
Speaker1: him. And I said,
Speaker1: no worries. I will
Speaker1: call him and let him
Speaker1: know he's been
Speaker1: removed.
Speaker1: You don't remember that.
Speaker2: Yeah, I remember.
Speaker2: I'm not going to speak to
Speaker2: him because I couldn't speak
Speaker2: to him anymore.
Speaker2: He hung up on me.
Speaker2: He was done. He was
Speaker2: like, you know,
Speaker2: get me
Speaker2: a,
Speaker2: should I forgot
Speaker2: her
Speaker2: Cindy on the line.
Speaker2: No, I'm not gonna get
Speaker2: Cindy on the line,
Speaker2: which is fine. My
Speaker2: concern now is,
Speaker2: and you shared with me
Speaker2: exactly how I
Speaker2: felt.
Speaker2: And I have T-Roc coming
Speaker2: back saying to me, like,
Speaker2: nope, you didn't feel that
Speaker2: way.
Speaker1: I didn't say you didn't
Speaker1: feel that way, but
Speaker1: I did say
Speaker1: that how
Speaker1: you, but
Speaker1: what
Speaker2: I am saying- That's what you said, I
Speaker2: wrote it down here.
Speaker2: That's
Speaker2: you.
Speaker1: What I'm saying
Speaker1: is
Speaker1: you
Speaker1: didn't give us any
Speaker1: facts
Speaker1: that we could
Speaker1: use to
Speaker1: justify
Speaker1: why we sent
Speaker1: this guy home
Speaker1: without pay.
Speaker1: What this guy
Speaker1: did, that made
Speaker1: you feel that way.
Speaker1: You were unable to
Speaker1: articulate
Speaker1: that.
Speaker2: Yeah, if that's how you feel during
Speaker2: your investigation,
Speaker2: great. I don't have a
Speaker2: problem with that.
Speaker2: If you say like, I
Speaker2: interviewed Gerardo just
Speaker2: now and I feel like, you know what,
Speaker2: Gerardo, after you explained to
Speaker2: me
Speaker2: everything
Speaker2: that you told me about it,
Speaker2: yeah, I don't see
Speaker2: it.
Speaker2: It can't hold
Speaker2: itself in court
Speaker2: of law. I
Speaker2: totally get that.
Speaker2: Even if you say, well,
Speaker2: even I'm bummed out, like
Speaker2: that's how I feel. And you're
Speaker2: like, that's not just
Speaker2: enough, which is fine.
Speaker2: That's okay. You're
Speaker2: doing your
Speaker2: investigation here.
Speaker2: That's what I'm saying,
Speaker2: Latasha. Like
Speaker2: then I guess this should have
Speaker2: happened
Speaker2: before,
Speaker2: you know, Diana
Speaker2: Love, you're
Speaker2: gonna send out that
Speaker2: email, you
Speaker2: know, with the
Speaker2: SB code of
Speaker2: California. Like if
Speaker2: it's gonna be that
Speaker2: serious,
Speaker2: but I shared with you at the
Speaker2: time, that's how it's
Speaker2: feeling. And that's how I
Speaker2: felt, right?
Speaker2: So I'm okay with
Speaker2: that. But my concern
Speaker2: is now,
Speaker2: coming back to me and
Speaker2: nope,
Speaker2: you weren't feeling threat. You
Speaker2: made it
Speaker2: up. You don't
Speaker2: believe me.
Speaker2: Facts
Speaker2: what did you say?
Speaker2: Feelings
Speaker2: need to be
Speaker2: facts.
Speaker1: No, I said
Speaker1: your feelings
Speaker1: are not
Speaker1: based on
Speaker1: any
Speaker1: objective
Speaker1: and reasonable
Speaker1: facts.
Speaker1: But that's what I
Speaker1: said.
Speaker1: Yeah.
Speaker1: You were
Speaker1: unable to
Speaker1: articulate for
Speaker1: me any
Speaker1: fact
Speaker1: that, for
Speaker1: example, if
Speaker1: you had
Speaker1: called the
Speaker1: police,
Speaker1: the police were going to
Speaker1: ask you,
Speaker1: OK, well,
Speaker1: what did he say
Speaker1: or do that
Speaker1: made you think
Speaker1: that that
Speaker1: he's a threat?
Speaker1: Because.
Speaker1: Because
Speaker1: just being
Speaker1: angry
Speaker1: by itself is
Speaker1: not a
Speaker1: threat.
Speaker1: angry, but
Speaker1: I'm not
Speaker1: threatening you and
Speaker1: I'm not going to
Speaker1: physically
Speaker1: harm you in
Speaker1: any way.
Speaker2: You weren't on that
Speaker2: call,
Speaker2: like his
Speaker2: tone of voice,
Speaker2: like you
Speaker2: weren't on that
Speaker2: call.
Speaker2: And it showed his anger by
Speaker2: his emails.
Speaker2: I haven't listened to his
Speaker2: voicemail. He didn't sound as
Speaker2: angry, but like he
Speaker2: continued texting me and
Speaker2: calling me.
Speaker1: Well, yeah, I've,
Speaker1: I've read the
Speaker1: emails and it
Speaker1: does come across
Speaker1: that he's
Speaker1: upset.
Speaker2: at the end of this,
Speaker2: he's
Speaker2: going
Speaker1: to
Speaker1: stab
Speaker1: anybody
Speaker1: or
Speaker1: like,
Speaker1: none of that
Speaker1: is what
Speaker1: he's saying. What he's
Speaker1: saying is I'm
Speaker1: angry and I'm going to
Speaker1: sue you.
Speaker2: Yeah, but at the end of the
Speaker2: day,
Speaker2: Latasha, you're
Speaker2: telling me that
Speaker2: I'm wrong.
Speaker2: You're disappointed.
Speaker2: Like, I was feeling
Speaker2: completely wrong. Like,
Speaker2: I just, I
Speaker2: don't know. I'm just
Speaker2: dumbfounded, I
Speaker2: guess. Again, I've
Speaker2: never been in this kind of
Speaker2: situation before. Never
Speaker2: had any...
Speaker1: Any
Speaker2: employee
Speaker2: goes off, but
Speaker2: I'm
Speaker1: just...
Speaker1: We're both
Speaker1: flabbergasted
Speaker1: here because
Speaker1: I...
Speaker2: I don't feel any
Speaker2: support from
Speaker2: HR at
Speaker2: all. It's like, now I'm
Speaker2: being
Speaker2: targeted.
Speaker2: I
Speaker1: feel like
Speaker1: HR went
Speaker1: all out to
Speaker1: support you.
Speaker1: And
Speaker1: I feel like,
Speaker1: like you
Speaker1: had us
Speaker1: jumping off
Speaker1: of a plank for
Speaker1: you
Speaker1: straight
Speaker1: into the ocean
Speaker1: with no
Speaker1: support
Speaker1: because
Speaker1: now
Speaker1: HR is
Speaker1: left.
Speaker1: No, let me be
Speaker1: clear.
Speaker1: We're left with the
Speaker1: egg on our
Speaker1: face,
Speaker1: justifying
Speaker1: why we sent an
Speaker1: employee
Speaker1: home
Speaker1: off
Speaker1: of your safe
Speaker1: though.
Speaker1: when there was
Speaker1: no legal
Speaker1: basis for us
Speaker1: to do that.
Speaker1: And we deprived
Speaker1: him of pay,
Speaker1: which he's already
Speaker1: complaining
Speaker1: about
Speaker1: without
Speaker1: proper
Speaker1: legal
Speaker1: basis,
Speaker1: because we
Speaker1: accepted
Speaker1: your word
Speaker1: for it,
Speaker1: that he was
Speaker1: threatening you.
Speaker2: And I told you
Speaker2: how I felt. And if you
Speaker2: don't believe that it was
Speaker2: enough, then that's
Speaker2: fine.
Speaker2: Then maybe you should have
Speaker2: called, maybe that's what I'm
Speaker2: saying,
Speaker2: Latasha. If it was
Speaker2: this serious, then
Speaker2: we should have had this
Speaker2: conversation
Speaker2: before we sent
Speaker2: that email to him about
Speaker2: the,
Speaker2: you know, safety
Speaker2: concern.
Speaker1: Clearly you're
Speaker1: right and the next
Speaker1: time we will make
Speaker1: sure whether this
Speaker1: is therapy or you're
Speaker1: actually reporting
Speaker1: an incident.
Speaker2: Thank you. But I
Speaker2: definitely did not
Speaker2: make this up.
Speaker1: Unbelievable.
Speaker1: My sentiments
Speaker1: exactly.
Speaker1: Unbelievable.
Speaker2: Unprofessional.
Speaker1: Yes, it was
Speaker1: very
Speaker1: unprofessional for
Speaker1: a manager to
Speaker1: accuse his
Speaker1: employee of
Speaker1: threatening him
Speaker1: when no
Speaker1: such threats were
Speaker1: actually
Speaker1: made.
Speaker2: Are we done
Speaker2: with this
Speaker2: conversation or I
Speaker2: mean, there's
Speaker2: really
Speaker1: been done.
Speaker1: Yes, we're done.
Speaker2: Oh, I've been
Speaker2: done. Okay.